Rashed Rahat

Full-stack Developer







+880 17 8909 3355

imrashedrahat@gmail.com

rashedrahat

Summary

4 years of experience as a full-stack (strong on the front end), delivering high-impact web solutions to clients across various industries. Capable of planning, creating, and testing several web applications that use a variety of technologies.

Education

2011

SSC

Noakhali Zilla School

2013

HSC

Noakhali Govt. College

2019

BS, SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

American International University-Bangladesh

Expertise

- HTML5, CSS3 & Tailwind CSS
- JavaScript & TypeScript
- React.js & Next.js
- Node.js & Express.js
- MySQL & MongoDB
- REST APIs & GraphQL
- Automation Testing
- GIT

Experience

Dec 2021 - Present

Shikho I Rangs Paramount Square, Floor 11, Banani, Dhaka

SDE II REACTJS ENGINEER

✓ Saved \$1M per year in operating costs by integrating third-party tools that provide the functionality to integrate app analytics and marketing.

✓ Debugged in-house products' codes and improved UI to improve functionality and performance by 15-25%.

 \checkmark Stay up to date on what needed to be updated in response to new release versions by adhering to the documentation.

 \checkmark Assist the junior developers with the design, development, deployment, and maintenance of all in-house products.

Skills: HTML · Tailwind CSS · Next.js · REST APIs · GraphQL

Mar 2021 - Nov 2021

Misfit Technologies Ltd. I 47 Road, 23 House, Banani, Dhaka

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (REACT.JS)

 \checkmark Utilized a core understanding of React to encourage better component lifecycle procedures, increasing turnaround speed by 24% while maintaining 100% deadline adherence.

√ Implemented a new responsive and mobile-first approach which increased mobile traffic by 20%.

Skills: HTML · CSS · Redux · Next.js · REST APIs

Jun 2019 - Mar 2021

Workspace InfoTech Limited I 12 Road, 12 House, Nikunja 2, Dhaka

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

✓ Completed training projects utilizing Node.js and React to create industry-standard web applications.

 \checkmark Performed testing, installation, configuration, and troubleshooting of various software programs.

✓ Developed 200+ SQL queries in MySQL and MongoDB.

Skills: HTML · CSS · React.is · Redux · Node.is · Express.is · MySQL · MongoDB

Reference

Available on request.